

Edward KingSoftware engineer

e: ed.king4967@gmail.com m: +1(970)412-0000

Personal Profile

I am a motivated, well-rounded, technically skilled individual who never stops learning. In college, I earned degrees in electrical engineering and English. Outside the classroom, I worked on a student satellite and a telecommunications project in Peru. Since then, I have worked as a web and firmware engineer and a teacher, living in three countries. Throughout, I have continued to build my core skills in software, web, and firmware development.

Technical Experience

Web developer at In-Situ

October 2016-May 2017

Working on a web application to aggregate water quality data. Worked on the front end in Angular JS, and the backend in Python and Flask.

Firmware Engineer at Netapp

August 2014 - July 2015

I worked in C++ on a cloud backup solution for Netapp's large storage systems. Our small team used Agile/Scrum methodology to keep on track. In addition to growing my proficiency in C++, I learned how to work on a small, efficient team within the difficult environment of a large organization.

Electrical Power Systems team member at University of Colorado Space Grant

October 2009 - June 2011

Worked on the power system of a research satellite to measure atmosphere composition at lower Earth orbit. In addition to hardware design and testing, wrote C and C++ code to regulate power and interface with other subsystems.

Key Skills

Web applications:

AngularJS	Flask	Postgres and sqlite
Python	Wordpress	Heroku
Django	PHP	Amazon EC2 and S3

Firmware and software:

C C#
C++ Java

Other relevant skills:

Android applications Git

Languages:

Spanish Chinese

Other Work Experience

English assistant teacher at IES San Agustin, Madrid

August 2017 - November 2017

Assistant-taught English as a second language in a Spanish classroom.

High school English teacher at Suzhou Foreign Language School

August 2015 - July 2016

Teaching reading and writing skills in foreign language high school to prepare students for Western universities.

Education

University of Colorado

Electrical and Computer Engineering and Creative Writing

Studied engineering fundamentals as well as hardware and software design. Completed projects including a microcontroller-controller robot and an Android app to detect notes played on a guitar.

Learned communication skills that let me work within a team and communicate with outside organizations.